<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://qingyuanyuu.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://qingyuanyuu.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-02-10T04:53:39+00:00</updated><id>https://qingyuanyuu.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">What Excites Me About AI &amp;amp; Computer Vision</title><link href="https://qingyuanyuu.github.io/blog/2025/find-research-lab/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Excites Me About AI &amp;amp; Computer Vision"/><published>2025-02-09T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-09T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://qingyuanyuu.github.io/blog/2025/find-research-lab</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://qingyuanyuu.github.io/blog/2025/find-research-lab/"><![CDATA[<p>Artificial intelligence is changing the world, and one of the most exciting fields within AI is <strong>computer vision</strong>. The ability of machines to “see” and understand the world around them has always fascinated me. From self-driving cars to medical imaging and even augmented reality, the possibilities seem endless.</p> <p>In this blog post, I want to share why I’m so passionate about AI and computer vision and how I hope to contribute to this field in the future.</p> <h4 id="the-power-of-ai--computer-vision">The Power of AI &amp; Computer Vision</h4> <p>Computer vision allows machines to analyze and interpret visual data, just like humans do—but often faster and with greater precision. Some real-world applications that excite me include:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Autonomous Vehicles</strong> – Teaching cars to perceive the road and make real-time decisions.</li> <li><strong>Medical Imaging</strong> – AI-powered diagnostics that can detect diseases from X-rays and MRIs.</li> <li><strong>Facial Recognition &amp; Biometrics</strong> – Enhancing security and authentication systems.</li> <li><strong>Augmented Reality (AR) &amp; Virtual Reality (VR)</strong> – Creating immersive digital experiences.</li> <li><strong>Agriculture &amp; Environmental Monitoring</strong> – Using drones to analyze crops and detect environmental changes.</li> </ul> <p>Each of these applications has the potential to transform industries and improve lives, which is what makes this field so exciting to me.</p> <h4 id="how-i-got-interested-in-computer-vision">How I Got Interested in Computer Vision</h4> <p>My interest in computer vision started with <strong>[ece176]</strong>. As I learned more, I realized how powerful AI-driven vision systems could be.</p> <p>Some key moments in my learning journey:</p> <ol> <li><strong>[First exposure to AI/ML]</strong> – I took a class or read a paper that introduced me to AI.</li> <li><strong>[First project]</strong> – I worked on <strong>[handwritten number detection]</strong>, which deepened my interest.</li> <li><strong>[Recent research/paper that inspired you]</strong> – I came across <strong>[mention paper or breakthrough]</strong>, which made me want to explore further.</li> </ol> <h4 id="what-i-want-to-explore-next">What I Want to Explore Next</h4> <p>As I continue my studies at UCSD, I’m eager to:</p> <ul> <li>Join a research lab focused on AI and computer vision.</li> <li>Work on projects related to <strong>[image segmentation, object detection, generative models, and so on]</strong>.</li> <li>Contribute to open-source projects or competitions like Kaggle.</li> <li>Learn more about deep learning frameworks like TensorFlow and PyTorch.</li> </ul> <h4 id="the-future-of-ai--computer-vision">The Future of AI &amp; Computer Vision</h4> <p>Looking ahead, I believe that AI-powered vision systems will become even more advanced, with applications we can’t even imagine yet. Some areas I’m excited to follow:</p> <ul> <li><strong>AI-powered creativity</strong> – Using computer vision for art, music, and design.</li> <li><strong>Ethics &amp; bias in AI</strong> – Ensuring fairness and transparency in AI-driven decisions.</li> <li><strong>Generalized AI models</strong> – Creating AI systems that can adapt to multiple tasks like humans.</li> </ul> <hr/> <blockquote> <p>“The real voyage of discovery consists not in seeking new landscapes, but in having new eyes.”<br/> — Marcel Proust</p> </blockquote> <p>I’m excited to dive deeper into AI and computer vision and connect with others who share this passion. If you’re working on something interesting in this field, feel free to reach out! 🚀</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="AI,"/><category term="computer"/><category term="vision,"/><category term="machine"/><category term="learning,"/><category term="research"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring my passion for AI and computer vision and why I find it so fascinating.]]></summary></entry></feed>